[
  {
    "question": "Why so JavaScript and Java have similar name?",
    "options": [
      "JavaScript is a stripped-down version of Java",
      "JavaScript's syntax is loosely based on Java's",
      "They both originated on the island of Java",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "JavaScript's syntax is loosely based on Java's"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a user views a page containing a JavaScript program, which machine actually executes the script?",
    "options": [
      "The User's machine running a Web browser",
      "The Web server",
      "A central machine deep within Netscape's corporate offices",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "The User's machine running a Web browser"
  },
  {
    "question": "______ JavaScript is also called client-side JavaScript.",
    "options": [
      "Microsoft",
      "Navigator",
      "LiveWire",
      "Native"
    ],
    "answer": "Navigator"
  },
  {
    "question": "__________ JavaScript is also called server-side JavaScript.",
    "options": [
      "Microsoft",
      "Navigator",
      "LiveWire",
      "Native"
    ],
    "answer": "LiveWire"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are variables used for in JavaScript Programs?",
    "options": [
      "Storing numbers, dates, or other values",
      "Varying randomly",
      "Causing high-school algebra flashbacks",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "Storing numbers, dates, or other values"
  },
  {
    "question": "_____ JavaScript statements embedded in an HTML page can respond to user events such as mouse-clicks, form input, and page navigation.",
    "options": [
      "Client-side",
      "Server-side",
      "Local",
      "Native"
    ],
    "answer": "Client-side"
  },
  {
    "question": "What should appear at the very end of your JavaScript? The <script LANGUAGE=\"JavaScript\"> tag",
    "options": [
      "The </script>",
      "The <script>",
      "The END statement",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "The </script>"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following can't be done with client-side JavaScript?",
    "options": [
      "Validating a form",
      "Sending a form's contents by email",
      "Storing the form's contents to a database file on the server",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "Storing the form's contents to a database file on the server"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are capabilities of functions in JavaScript?",
    "options": [
      "Return a value",
      "Accept parameters and Return a value",
      "Accept parameters",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "Accept parameters"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a valid JavaScript variable name?",
    "options": [
      "2names",
      "_first_and_last_names",
      "FirstAndLast",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "2names"
  },
  {
    "question": "______ tag is an extension to HTML that can enclose any number of JavaScript statements.",
    "options": [
      "<SCRIPT>",
      "<BODY>",
      "<HEAD>",
      "<TITLE>"
    ],
    "answer": "<SCRIPT>"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does JavaScript store dates in a date object?",
    "options": [
      "The number of milliseconds since January 1st, 1970",
      "The number of days since January 1st, 1900",
      "The number of seconds since Netscape's public stock offering.",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "The number of milliseconds since January 1st, 1970"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following attribute can hold the JavaScript version?",
    "options": [
      "LANGUAGE",
      "SCRIPT",
      "VERSION",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "LANGUAGE"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the correct JavaScript syntax to write \"Hello World\"?",
    "options": [
      "System.out.println(\"Hello World\")",
      "println (\"Hello World\")",
      "document.write(\"Hello World\")",
      "response.write(\"Hello World\")"
    ],
    "answer": "document.write(\"Hello World\")"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following way can be used to indicate the LANGUAGE attribute?",
    "options": [
      "<LANGUAGE=\"JavaScriptVersion\">",
      "<SCRIPT LANGUAGE=\"JavaScriptVersion\">",
      "<SCRIPT LANGUAGE=\"JavaScriptVersion\"> JavaScript statements…</SCRIPT>",
      "<SCRIPT LANGUAGE=\"JavaScriptVersion\"!> JavaScript statements…</SCRIPT>"
    ],
    "answer": "<SCRIPT LANGUAGE=\"JavaScriptVersion\"> JavaScript statements…</SCRIPT>"
  },
  {
    "question": "Inside which HTML element do we put the JavaScript?",
    "options": [
      "<js>",
      "<scripting>",
      "<script>",
      "<javascript>"
    ],
    "answer": "<script>"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the correct syntax for referring to an external script called \" abc.js\"?",
    "options": [
      "<script href=\" abc.js\">",
      "<script name=\" abc.js\">",
      "<script src=\" abc.js\">",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "<script src=\" abc.js\">"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which types of image maps can be used with JavaScript?",
    "options": [
      "Server-side image maps",
      "Client-side image maps",
      "Server-side image maps and Client-side image maps",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "Client-side image maps"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following navigator object properties is the same in both Netscape and IE?",
    "options": [
      "navigator.appCodeName",
      "navigator.appName",
      "navigator.appVersion",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "navigator.appCodeName"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is the correct way to write a JavaScript array?",
    "options": [
      "var txt = new Array(1:\"tim\",2:\"kim\",3:\"jim\")",
      "var txt = new Array:1=(\"tim\")2=(\"kim\")3=(\"jim\")",
      "var txt = new Array(\"tim\",\"kim\",\"jim\")",
      "var txt = new Array=\"tim\",\"kim\",\"jim\""
    ],
    "answer": "var txt = new Array(\"tim\",\"kim\",\"jim\")"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the <noscript> tag do?",
    "options": [
      "Enclose text to be displayed by non-JavaScript browsers.",
      "Prevents scripts on the page from executing.",
      "Describes certain low-budget movies.",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "Enclose text to be displayed by non-JavaScript browsers."
  },
  {
    "question": "If para1 is the DOM object for a paragraph, what is the correct syntax to change the text within the paragraph?",
    "options": [
      "\"New Text\"?",
      "para1.value=\"New Text\";",
      "para1.firstChild.nodeValue= \"New Text\";",
      "para1.nodeValue=\"New Text\";"
    ],
    "answer": "para1.firstChild.nodeValue= \"New Text\";"
  },
  {
    "question": "JavaScript entities start with _______ and end with _________.",
    "options": [
      "Semicolon, colon",
      "Semicolon, Ampersand",
      "Ampersand, colon",
      "Ampersand, semicolon"
    ],
    "answer": "Ampersand, semicolon"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best describes JavaScript?",
    "options": [
      "a low-level programming language.",
      "a scripting language precompiled in the browser.",
      "a compiled scripting language.",
      "an object-oriented scripting language."
    ],
    "answer": "an object-oriented scripting language."
  },
  {
    "question": "Choose the server-side JavaScript object?",
    "options": [
      "FileUpLoad",
      "Function",
      "File",
      "Date"
    ],
    "answer": "File"
  },
  {
    "question": "Choose the client-side JavaScript object?",
    "options": [
      "Database",
      "Cursor",
      "Client",
      "FileUpLoad"
    ],
    "answer": "FileUpLoad"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not considered a JavaScript operator?",
    "options": [
      "new",
      "this",
      "delete",
      "typeof"
    ],
    "answer": "new"
  },
  {
    "question": "______ method evaluates a string of JavaScript code in the context of the specified object.",
    "options": [
      "Eval",
      "ParseInt",
      "ParseFloat",
      "Efloat"
    ],
    "answer": "Eval"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following event fires when the form element loses the focus: <button>, <input>, <label>, <select>, <textarea>?",
    "options": [
      "onfocus",
      "onblur",
      "onclick",
      "ondblclick"
    ],
    "answer": "onblur"
  },
  {
    "question": "The syntax of Eval is ________________",
    "options": [
      "[objectName.]eval(numeriC.",
      "[objectName.]eval(string)",
      "[EvalName.]eval(string)",
      "[EvalName.]eval(numeriC."
    ],
    "answer": "[objectName.]eval(string)"
  },
  {
    "question": "JavaScript is interpreted by _________",
    "options": [
      "Client",
      "Server",
      "Object",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "Client"
  },
  {
    "question": "Using _______ statement is how you test for a specific condition.",
    "options": [
      "Select",
      "If",
      "Switch",
      "For"
    ],
    "answer": "If"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the structure of an if statement?",
    "options": [
      "if (conditional expression is true) thenexecute this codeend if",
      "if (conditional expression is true)execute this codeend if",
      "if (conditional expression is true) {then execute this code>->}",
      "if (conditional expression is true) then {execute this code}"
    ],
    "answer": "if (conditional expression is true) {then execute this code>->}"
  },
  {
    "question": "How to create a Date object in JavaScript?",
    "options": [
      "dateObjectName = new Date([parameters])",
      "dateObjectName.new Date([parameters])",
      "dateObjectName := new Date([parameters])",
      "dateObjectName Date([parameters])"
    ],
    "answer": "dateObjectName = new Date([parameters])"
  },
  {
    "question": "The _______ method of an Array object adds and/or removes elements from an array.",
    "options": [
      "Reverse",
      "Shift",
      "Slice",
      "Splice"
    ],
    "answer": "Splice"
  },
  {
    "question": "To set up the window to capture all Click events, we use which of the following statement?",
    "options": [
      "window.captureEvents(Event.CLICK);",
      "window.handleEvents (Event.CLICK);",
      "window.routeEvents(Event.CLICK );",
      "window.raiseEvents(Event.CLICK );"
    ],
    "answer": "window.captureEvents(Event.CLICK);"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tag(s) can handle mouse events in Netscape?",
    "options": [
      "<IMG>",
      "<A>",
      "<BR>",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "<A>"
  },
  {
    "question": "____________ is the tainted property of a window object.",
    "options": [
      "Pathname",
      "Protocol",
      "Defaultstatus",
      "Host"
    ],
    "answer": "Defaultstatus"
  },
  {
    "question": "To enable data tainting, the end user sets the _________ environment variable.",
    "options": [
      "ENABLE_TAINT",
      "MS_ENABLE_TAINT",
      "NS_ENABLE_TAINT",
      "ENABLE_TAINT_NS"
    ],
    "answer": "NS_ENABLE_TAINT"
  },
  {
    "question": "In JavaScript, _________ is an object of the target language data type that encloses an object of the source language.",
    "options": [
      "a wrapper",
      "a link",
      "a cursor",
      "a form"
    ],
    "answer": "a wrapper"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a JavaScript object is sent to Java, the runtime engine creates a Java wrapper of type ___________",
    "options": [
      "ScriptObject",
      "JSObject",
      "JavaObject",
      "Jobject"
    ],
    "answer": "JSObject"
  },
  {
    "question": "_______ class provides an interface for invoking JavaScript methods and examining JavaScript properties.",
    "options": [
      "ScriptObject",
      "JSObject",
      "JavaObject",
      "Jobject"
    ],
    "answer": "JSObject"
  },
  {
    "question": "_________ is a wrapped Java array, accessed from within JavaScript code.",
    "options": [
      "JavaArray",
      "JavaClass",
      "JavaObject",
      "JavaPackage"
    ],
    "answer": "JavaArray"
  },
  {
    "question": "A ________ object is a reference to one of the classes in a Java package, such as netscape.javascript .",
    "options": [
      "JavaArray",
      "JavaClass",
      "JavaObject",
      "JavaPackage"
    ],
    "answer": "JavaClass"
  },
  {
    "question": "The JavaScript exception is available to the Java code as an instance of __________",
    "options": [
      "netscape.javascript.JSObject",
      "netscape.javascript.JSException",
      "netscape.plugin.JSException",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "netscape.javascript.JSException"
  },
  {
    "question": "To automatically open the console when a JavaScript error occurs which of the following is added to prefs.js?",
    "options": [
      "user_pref(\" javascript.console.open_on_error\", false);",
      "user_pref(\"javascript.console.open_error \", true);",
      "user_pref(\"javascript.console.open_error \", false);",
      "user_pref(\"javascript.console.open_on_error\", true);"
    ],
    "answer": "user_pref(\"javascript.console.open_on_error\", true);"
  },
  {
    "question": "To open a dialog box each time an error occurs, which of the following is added to prefs.js?",
    "options": [
      "user_pref(\"javascript.classic.error_alerts\", true);",
      "user_pref(\"javascript.classic.error_alerts \", false);",
      "user_pref(\"javascript.console.open_on_error \", true);",
      "user_pref(\"javascript.console.open_on_error \", false);"
    ],
    "answer": "user_pref(\"javascript.classic.error_alerts\", true);"
  },
  {
    "question": "The syntax of a blur method in a button object is ______________",
    "options": [
      "Blur()",
      "Blur(contrast)",
      "Blur(value)",
      "Blur(depth)"
    ],
    "answer": "Blur()"
  },
  {
    "question": "The syntax of capture events method for document object is ______________",
    "options": [
      "captureEvents()",
      "captureEvents(args eventType)",
      "captureEvents(eventType)",
      "captureEvents(eventVal)"
    ],
    "answer": "captureEvents(eventType)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The syntax of close method for document object is ______________",
    "options": [
      "Close(doC.",
      "Close(object)",
      "Close(val)",
      "Close()"
    ],
    "answer": "Close()"
  },
  {
    "question": "<script type=\"text/javascript\">\nx=4+\"4\";\ndocument.write(x);\n</script>\nOutput------?",
    "options": [
      "44",
      "8",
      "4",
      "Error output"
    ],
    "answer": "44"
  },
  {
    "question": "Is it possible to nest functions in JavaScript?",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "answer": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "<script>\ndocument.write(navigator.appCodeName);\n</script>",
    "options": [
      "get code name of the browser of a visitor",
      "set code name of the browser of a visitor",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "get code name of the browser of a visitor"
  },
  {
    "question": "Scripting language are",
    "options": [
      "High Level Programming language",
      "Assembly Level programming language",
      "Machine level programming language"
    ],
    "answer": "High Level Programming language"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which best explains getSelection()?",
    "options": [
      "Returns the VALUE of a selected OPTION.",
      "Returns document.URL of the window in focus.",
      "Returns the value of cursor-selected text",
      "Returns the VALUE of a checked radio input."
    ],
    "answer": "Returns the value of cursor-selected text"
  },
  {
    "question": "Choose the client-side JavaScript object:",
    "options": [
      "Database",
      "Cursor",
      "Client",
      "FileUpLoad"
    ],
    "answer": "FileUpLoad"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is mean by \"this\" keyword in javascript?",
    "options": [
      "It refers current object",
      "It referes previous object",
      "It is variable which contains value",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "It refers current object"
  },
  {
    "question": "In JavaScript, Window.prompt() method return true or false value ?",
    "options": [
      "False",
      "True"
    ],
    "answer": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "<script language=\"javascript\">\nfunction x()\n{\ndocument.write(2+5+\"8\");\n}\n</script>",
    "options": [
      "258",
      "Error",
      "7",
      "78"
    ],
    "answer": "78"
  },
  {
    "question": "<script type=\"text/javascript\">\nvar s = \"9123456 or 80000?\";\nvar pattern = /d{4}/;\nvar output = s.match(pattern);\ndocument.write(output);\n</script>",
    "options": [
      "9123",
      "91234",
      "80000",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "9123"
  }
]
